Romain Giovanetti

romain@giovanetti.fr 4 04 23 12 57 74

n giovanetti.fr

Profile

I am a Full-Stack Engineer with ten years of international experience in app design, development, and maintenance.

Creative and curious, I value quality no matter what I am making.

I like in particular **\$\ointigeq\$ web technologies**, and I'm focused on continually improving the 2 user experience.

Main Skills

Fields

Critical Thinking, User Experience, Problem Solving, Software Architecture, Design, and Software Development Life Cycle.

Technologies

Symfony, React, Java EE, MobX, Node.js, TypeScript, RESTFul APIs, Elasticsearch, Python, Jest, MySQL, Redux, SASS, Oracle, Storybook, and SOAP.

Languages

French •••• English •••• German ••000

Experience

Full-Stack Engineer

Today November 2023 Freelance, Saint Memmie, France

- Redesigned and optimized the front-end of La Maison De L'Eleveur's website to enhance user engagement, simplify navigation, and boost conversion rates as part of its 10th-anniversary update:
- Refactored and upgraded the back-end of La Maison De L'Eleveur's website from Symfony 4 to Symfony 5, ensuring improved performance and maintainability;
- Developed a custom configuration interface for the previously static website of Champagne Carole Haudot's website.

May 2023 October 2023

Software Engineer (Frontend)

Canva, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia

- Enhanced user experience by implementing infinite scroll functionality for an event timeline. This feature involved data retrieval and consolidation from multiple endpoints, sorted by an efficient sorting algorithm;
- Designed a special theme module to facilitate seamless integration of unique theme decorations (e.g., April Fool's, Christmas) into the web application;
- Successfully refactored codebase by identifying and replacing deprecated component and service usages, enhancing application stability and performance;

- Implemented comprehensive unit tests for component presenters that were previously lacking test coverage;
- Actively provided high-quality support to team specialists in need through the team's public Slack channel;
- Took an active role in shaping an 18-month strategy focused on mitigating linear cost escalation caused by user base growth. This involved leveraging machine learning, language models (OpenAI), and enhancing the usability of specialist tools.

December 2019 April 2023

Full-Stack Engineer

Freelance, Saint Memmie, France

- Designed and implemented a custom made system to automatically generate and send quotes (PDF files) to La Maison De L'Eleveur's customers;
- Designed and built several custom product assistants for the website of La Maison De L'Eleveur, to ease the purchase of configurable products;
- Designed and implemented custom product pricing modules for the website of La Maison De L'Eleveur, to compute dynamic prices based on several factors (product's custom specifications and quantity/length);
- Added several tests classes to the website of La Maison De L'Eleveur, to avoid regressions;
- Refactored and upgraded, from Symfony 3 to Symfony 4, the website of La Maison De L'Eleveur;
- Designed and implemented a custom order system for the website of La Maison De L'Eleveur;
- Designed and built the website of Champagne Carole Haudot. This website features a simple online shop, using React and React Redux.

May 2018 November 2019

Software Developer

Coface North America, Princeton, NJ, United States of America

- ★ V.I.E. (International Volunteer in Business) in the USA (New York)
- Maintained policy management applications and collection back office support applications (back-end and front-end);
- Participated in solution architecture and design;
- Designed and developed interfaces to facilitate communication between different software applications;
- Created debug tools related to PDF generation;
- Maintained the DEV team wiki;
- Maintained legacy code and refactored it when it was possible;
- Following a penetration test, reinforced the security of the main application and its side apps, including a password encryption upgrade, and a complete rework of the "I forgot my password" process.
- Blog about this chapter of my life: vie-usa.giovanetti.fr

September 2017 April 2018

Full-Stack Engineer

Freelance, Saint Memmie, France

- Started my own business in France as sole trader;
- Migrated the website of La Maison De L'Eleveur from Symfony 2 to Symfony 3;
- Introduced new features to the website of La Maison De L'Eleveur, using various web technologies (Symfony 2/3, MySQL, Bootstrap, and jQuery).

October 2014 August 2017

Research Engineer / Full-Stack Engineer

CNRS / Université de Lille / CRIStAL Lab. / NOCE Team, Lille, France

- Published two publications in the IEEE international conference on Advances in Social Network Analysis and Mining 2016 (ASONAM);
- Listed and evaluated the existing ways to collect and process tweets for social network analysis;
- Built and maintained a distributed platform for collecting and processing up to two millions tweets per day, with a complete data retention period of 2 years, powered by Elasticsearch and TensorFlow;
- Obesigned and built an internal API to control this distributed platform remotely, and offer secured ways to retrieve the processed data:
- Designed and built a powerful and easy to use dashboard, to present safely the processed data in a meaningful way to third party users, made possible by a complete asynchronous stack approach, featuring AngularJS and Node.js;
- Studied methods and developed software prototypes to extract sentiments, gender and geolocation from tweets, using simple algorithms and recursive neural networks.

June 2014 September 2014

Full-Stack Engineer

La Maison De L'Eleveur, Vouziers, France

- Revamped La Maison De L'Eleveur's online product catalogue (more than 1500 references):
- Rebuilt from scratch La Maison De L'Eleveur's e-commerce website, within 3 months, using Symfony 2, Bootstrap and jQuery;
- Prototyped and implemented an intuitive user interface to help customers configure and purchase custom tailored steel sheets;
- Deployed the new website, maintained it, and improved it according to customer feedback;

March 2013 February 2014

Research Engineer

CNRS / Université de Lille / CRIStAL Lab. / NOCE Team, Lille, France

- Designed and built custom made bracelets that communicated with each other, using Arduino nano, Xbee modules, batteries, handmade housings, vibrators, RFID chips, and other small components;
- Designed and built custom made contactless quiz terminals, using Arduino mega, ethernet shields, RFID shields, and other small components;

- Created a main control system (Java + MongoDB) to remotely manage and configure the custom made devices, and log their usages;
- ❷ Built a dashboard (Node.js + Express + MongoDB) to filter the collected usages data and present them in a meaningful way;
- Deployed the custom made devices and the main control system in the Museum of Fine Arts of Tourcoing, France, and conducted user experience evaluations.



Discover more experiences and side projects on giovanetti.fr/resume

Education Master's Degree in Computer Science

Université de Lille 1 - Sciences et technologies, France - Graduated 2013

★ Exchange program (Erasmus), at TU Graz, Austria, in 2022.

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Université de Lille 1 - Sciences et technologies, France - Graduated 2011

University Technology Diploma in Computer Science

Université de Reims Champagne-Ardenne, France - Graduated 2010

References Available upon request.

Links

- ngiovanetti.fr
- github.com/ganoninc
- in linkedin.com/in/romainjg
- stackoverflow.com/users/2815175/r-giovanetti
- \/> leetcode.com/RomainJG

EU-AU-2024-11-20 Page 4 of 4